<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brendan Cooley</title>
    <link>http://brendancooley.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brendan Cooley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://brendancooley.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http://brendancooley.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brendancooley.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description>I am currently Senior Data Scientist at Big League Advance. I received my Ph.D. in Politics at Princeton University in 2020. My dissertation, “Trade Policy in the Shadow of Power,” studied how military coercion affects the structure of the international economy &amp;ndash; where economic activity is located and who trades with whom. In another line of research, I study exchange and violence in black markets. At Princeton, I taught the Politics Department’s summer math course for incoming graduate students, along with Daniel Gibbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://brendancooley.github.io/notes/dists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brendancooley.github.io/notes/dists/</guid>
      <description>Calculating Historical Intercapital Distances Last updated 10 January 2018
Military power degrades with distance. Fighting a war on another continent is, for most militaries, more difficult than fighting at home. Studies of conflict frequently employ capital-to-capital distance (or some transformation of this metric) as one proxy for this loss of strength from power projection (see, for example, (Gartzke and Braithwaite (2011)). Combined with data on territorial contiguity, these metrics can provide us with a picture of the geographic constraints facing countries contemplating war with one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://brendancooley.github.io/notes/icews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brendancooley.github.io/notes/icews/</guid>
      <description>Read and Clean ICEWS Coded Event Data Last updated 11 April 2018
Datasets that researchers use to measure conflict in international relations are generally coarse. The Correlates of War (COW) Project&amp;rsquo;s Militarized Interstate Dispute data records threats, displays, and uses of military force between 1816 and 2010 and COW&amp;rsquo;s interstate war data records conflicts which resulted in at least 1,000 battle deaths. Both MIDs and wars are exceedingly unusual. Yet the &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo; of international relations happens every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://brendancooley.github.io/other/epbt_pricesviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brendancooley.github.io/other/epbt_pricesviz/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://brendancooley.github.io/projects/epbt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://brendancooley.github.io/projects/epbt/</guid>
      <description>Estimating Policy Barriers to Trade   testing
 testing testing testing
 300 Fisher Hall \
Princeton University \
Princeton, NJ 08544 \
bcooley@princeton.edu
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
